As we saw in the first lesson on Google Analytics,
在有关 Google Analytics 的第一节课中
in order to see data in Google Analytics you need to
我们了解到要想在 Google Analytics 获得所需数据
insert the code Google provides on every page of your web site.
我们需要在网站的每个页面插入一段 Google 提供的代码
This code will collect the data.
那段代码将负责收集数据
For every page accessed by a user,
对于用户访问的每个页面
the referring link is part of the data collected by this code.
其推荐链接也将纳入这段代码收集的数据中
The referring link is the url of the web page that
推荐链接是包含可跳转至
has the link to use it clicked on to get to your site.
你的网站的那个网页的 url
Now, that works if the link is part of content on a site.
如果某网站的内容中包含你的网站跳转链接 那它就是你的推荐链接
For instance, if I write a blog post and I link to a piece of
例如 假设我写了一篇博客 并在其中添加了
clothing you can find on Betabrand you will see my blog is the referring url.
Betabrand 某件在售服装商品的链接 那么你将看到我的博客就是推荐链接
That's an organic referral.
这属于免费推荐
No one paid for it.
没有人为此付费
The link was established organically.
这个链接是自然建立的
It works a bit different for ads and marketing campaigns.
而广告和营销活动有一些不同
The information that's automatically picked up by analytics tools like Googles
Google Analytics 等分析工具自动收集的信息往往不够详尽
is not very informative and will often show the ad platform as a referrer.
只会将广告平台显示为推荐者
Let's look at this ad for Betabrand, for example.
我们以这条 Betabrand 广告为例进行阐述
If a user clicks on the ad,
当有用户点击这条广告时
it does not really help me to know that the ad was
分析工具并不能清楚地告诉我
served using Google advertising network for instance.
这条广告是通过例如 Google 广告网络投放的
As a marketer, I really want to know which ads the user clicked on,
作为一名营销人员 我很想知道用户具体是点击了哪条广告
and which campaign this was part of.
以及这个事件发生在哪个营销活动中
That's what I want to see in the data.
我希望能够在分析数据中了解这些信息
Fortunately, there is a way for you as a marketer to help the reporting tools a bit.
幸运的是 我们能够通过某些方法帮助分析工具识别这些信息
You do that by tagging every ad or campaign with information
你可以通过向广告或营销活动添加标记信息
that tells the analytics tool how to classify your ad as the referrer.
告诉分析工具如何将你的广告归类为推荐者
The way this works is as follows.
具体方法如下
When you create the ad or campaign you should add a small piece of
创建广告或营销活动时
extra text to the landing page url in the tool where you create the ad.
你应该在广告创建工具的着陆页网址中额外添加一段文本
That piece of text is called a UTM code,
这段文本即 UTM 代码
and it helps Google Analytics to classify the traffic
它可以帮助 Google Analytics
coming to your Web site via campaigns in the appropriate bucket.
将你的网站通过营销活动获得的流量归类到适当的小组中
For instance, traffic from display ads or traffic from search,
例如 来自助示广告的流量、
pay per click ads,
来自搜索 PPC（按点击量付费）广告的流量
traffic from social ads, et cetera.
来自社交广告的流量 等等
Now, when a user clicks on the ads,
现在 当有用户点击你的广告时
like here in the Betabrand example,
例如这条 Betabrand 广告
the landing page url shows the UTM code
着陆页网址中会显示你在创建营销活动时添加的 UTM 代码
or the piece of text that you added in setting up the campaign.
也就是那段文本
And that piece of text helps Google Analytics
这段文本将帮助 Google Analytics
classify the traffic as coming from a display ad.
正确地将流量归类为来自助示广告
If you want to learn more about how to create these links,
如需详细了解如何创建这种链接
you can find the information in the notes below.
你可以在下面的注释中找到相关信息
If you want to get a good understanding of which marketing campaigns are working for you,
如果你想要更好地了解营销活动的成效
it's really important to add these UTM codes for all campaigns.
那么请务必为所有营销活动添加这种 UTM 代码